I'm sure you're already familiar with scalar math.
相信你已经熟悉标量数学了
It's the normal addition, multiplication, and so on that
它就是平常的加法、乘法等等
you've probably been doing for most of your life.
你生活中的大部分时间都在用
But sometimes, like with neural networks,
但有时 就好像神经网络一样
you might need to perform those sorts of operations
你可能需要对很多数字执行运算
on a lot of numbers, maybe hundreds, thousands,
这些数字可能成百上千
even millions of them.
甚至可能上百万
Maybe you need to double them, square them, or divide them
你需要可能将它们翻一番 进行平方 或除以
all by the same number.
相同的数字
If you were writing a program, you
如果你在编写一个程序
might decide to make a loop where you iterate
你可能会创建一个循环 迭代
over every value and perform the same operation on each one
每个值 并一遍遍对每个值执行相同的
over and over, but matrices offer a better alternative.
操作 但是矩阵提供了更好的替代方法
If you have all of those numbers stored in a matrix,
如果你将所有的数字存储在一个矩阵中
you can perform element-wise operations on them.
你可以对它们执行元素级操作
That just means you'll treat the items in the matrix
这意味着你要在矩阵中分别处理它们
individually and perform the same operation on each one.
然后对每个上执行同样的操作
By the way, I say matrix, but this notion
顺便说下 我称之为矩阵 但是这一元素级概念
of element-wise math applies to data
适用于具有任意维数
with any number of dimensions.
的数据
To add two scalars, it's easy, like 2 plus 3 equals 5.
要加上两个标量的话 很简单 就像 2 + 3 = 5
To add a scalar and a matrix, it's
要加上一个标量和一个矩阵的话
practically the same thing.
实际上做法是相同的
Just add the scalar to each of the items in the matrix.
只需给矩阵当中的每一项加上一个标量
So 2 plus the matrix 1, 2, 3, 4 equals the matrix 3, 4, 5, 6.
所以 2 加上矩阵当中的 1、2、3、4 就得到了矩阵当中的 3、4、5、6
You can do the same thing with other math operators, too.
你也可以在没有另一个数学运算符的情况下执行相同的操作
Here's a real world example.
来看一个实际例子
Let's say we have a matrix of values
假设我们有一个值矩阵
that represents the red color channel of an image.
代表图像的红色通道
Assuming we're using our RGB colors,
假设我们在使用 RGB 色彩
each value will be a single byte ranging from 0 to 255.
每个值是单个字节 范围从 0 到 255
But let's say we want to normalize these values
但是如果说我们要归一化这些值
and convert them all to floating point values
并把它们都转化为浮点值
in the range from 0 to 1.
范围从 0 到 1
Easy.
那很简单
We just divide the matrix element-wise by 255.
我们只需将此矩阵在元素级别除以 255
By the way don't worry if you don't
顺便说一下 如果你不知道
know what normalizing means you'll
归一化是什么意思 不用担心
learn more about that later in the course.
你会在稍后的课程中更详细地了解
And this doesn't just work with scalars in matrices.
这不仅适用于矩阵当中的标量
You can also do element-wise math
你还可以在两个不同矩阵的所有元素之间
between all of the elements within two different matrices.
进行元素级数学计算
For this to work, the matrices have to be the same shape.
要使它成功 这两个矩阵的形状要一样
For example, here we have a pair of two-by-two matrices.
就比如说 这里我们有一对 2 x 2 的矩阵
To add them together, we just add
为了把它们加在一起
pairs of numbers that are at the same indices in each matrix,
我们只要把每个矩阵当中处于同一索引的数对加起来
and then we store the result at the same location in the answer
然后将答案存储在答案矩阵中的
matrix.
相同位置
So at index 1,1, we'd have the result
所以在索引 1,1 处 我们将获得
of adding the 1 plus the 2, which is 3.
1 + 2 的结果 也就是 3
And at index 1,2, we'd have the result
在索引 1,2 处 我们会获得
of adding the 3 plus the 4, which is 7, and so on.
3 + 4 的结果 也就是 7 以此类推
Now just like before, how I said you can do any normal math
跟前面我所说的你可以在标量和矩阵之间
operations element-wise between scalars and matrices,
进行任何常规的数学运算一样
you could also perform any of those operations
你也可以在两个形状相同的矩阵
between corresponding elements of two
的对应元素之间
identically shaped matrices.
执行这些运算